Guide to the Nell Mondy papers, 1932-2005.
Mondy, Nell papers, 1932-2005
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nell Mondy papers, 1932-2005.
23-14-2663
Nell I.(Nell Irene), Mondy 1921-
23.9 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, Photographs, Printed Materials, Videos, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Annual reports, speeches, photographs, and other papers, particularly pertaining to Mondy's teaching career.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Nutrition, Cornell University.
Nell Mondy received her bachelor's degree from Ouachita Baptist University, her M.A. from the University of Texas at Austin (1945) and her Ph.D. (1953) from Cornell. Her early research dealt with vitamin B6, folic acid, vitamin B12 and enzymes in choline metabolism, but the majority of her time was spent studying various aspects of the potato. Dr. Mondy was appointed an associate professor of food and nutrition at Cornell in 1953, became a professor in 1961, and retired in 1992.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Annual reports, speeches, photographs, and other papers, particularly pertaining to Mondy's teaching career. Also, papers from Mondy's early years concerning family, high school, and Ouachita Baptist University, files on Graduate Women in Science and the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), and scrapbook and carved key for Sigma Delta Epsilon made by Dr. Viola Graham.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Mondy, Nell I.1921-; Mondy, Nell I.1921-; Graham, Viola.; American Association for the Advancement of Science.; Cornell University. Cornell Africa Committee.; Graduate Women in Science.; New York State College of Human Ecology.; Ouachita Baptist University.; Sigma Delta Epsilon.
Subjects:
Nutrition--Study and teaching.; Nutrition--Research.; Women college teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical
Series II. Teaching
Series III. Potato Research
Series IV. Honors
Series V. Associations/Institutes
Series VI. Speeches
Series VII. Workshops
Series VIII. Publications/Clippings
Series IX. Africa
Series X. Cornell
Series XI. Correspondence
Series XII. Subject Files
Series XIII. Ephemera
Series XIV. Videos, Tape Recordings, Photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- I. Biographical
  - Early Years
    - Grandparents (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Father (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mother (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Family Documents - Marriage License - Family Photographs (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Hometown - Pocahontas, Arkansas (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Birth Announcement (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Baby Book (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Early Years (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Certificate of Promotion (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Award of Honor, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Grammar School Work (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 6th Grade Valedictory (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - High School Diploma (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - High School Yearbook - Chieftan (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 12th Grade Valedictory (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - First Place in English - 12th Grade (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - High School Band (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - First Boyfriend (Lowell Gibbs) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - 20th Class Reunion (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - 40th Pocahontas Reunion (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - 50th Class Reunion (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - 55th Class Reunion (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - High School Centennial, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - The Early Years - Review of Family History (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Coat of Arms - Carroll Family (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Sample of Nell's hair at different ages (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Early Years A Addition: Evangeline poetry, Junior High School Diploma (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Early Years B Addition: Mother, Pocahantas, Pratt Family (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Ouachita Baptist University
    - Ouachita: Becoming a Chemist, 1939-1943 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Ouachita Scholarship - Nell Philosophy (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Ouachita Honor Roll (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Ouachita Band (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Ouachita Class Reports (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - University Grades (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Ouachita Campus "Who's Who", 1941-1943 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Ouachita Yearbook, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Ouachita Yearbook, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Ouachita Classmates (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Ouachita Activities (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Ouachita 50th Reunion (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Freshman Comments to N. Mondy (senior) about seniors (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Mrs. Winburn - Dean of Dorm - Views on Women Education (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Ouachita - Vice President of Student Government (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Ouachita Faculty Catalogue, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Ouachita graduation - B.S. degree, 1943-01 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Quachita graduation - B.A. degree, 1943-08 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Ouachita Faculty, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Offer Ouachita Faculty Position, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Advisory Board (Ouachita Alum), 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Former Students Association, 1954, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Alumni Appreciation from Pres. Phelps, Alum Video:: Recruitment, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Mondy- Provine Scholarship Announcement, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Mondy - Provine Scholarship, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Distinguished Alumna Award, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Mondy Provine Scholarship, D. Grant President, 1981, 1961-1985 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Mondy Provine Scholarship, D. Grant President, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Dr. Roger Harrod, Vice President for Development, 1985-12-05, 1986-08-01 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Nell Mondy Lecture Series, Ben Elrod President (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Ouachita - Nell Mondy Lectureship (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Ouachita Burlett-Williams Lecturer, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Frances Crawford - Registrar while Mondy a student, 1945-1967 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Vice Chair Ouachita at 100 Alumni Campaign, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Ouachita Centennial, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Corresponding Mrs. Margaret Wright - Director Corp and Foundation Program (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Dr. William Cook - V.P. Development - Lecture Series, 1991-01-12 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Ouachita slide videos, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - President Dr. J.R. Grant (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Professor E.A. Provine (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - President Dr. Daniel Grant (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - President Ben Elrod, 1989-1998 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - President Andrew Westmoreland, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Ouachita Circle, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Class of 1943 - Endowed Scholarship Fund (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Book of Honor: Recipients of Provine-Mondy Scholarship, 1965-1998 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - N. Mondy Lecture Series Agreement, 1991-11-08, 1995-05-17 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - N. Mondy Lecture Series (Box 6, Folder 73)
      - #1 Tobias, 1993-09
      - #2 Parks, 1996-02
      - #3 Olna, 1997-05
      - # 4 Bourne, 1998-11
    - Nell I. Mondy Organic Laboratory - Jones Science Center - Dedication, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - President Elrod's Report, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Alumni Tiger Network (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Plaque - Vice Chair Ouachita at 100 Alumni Campaign (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Advisory Board, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Vice President Student Government, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Centennial, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Birkett Williams Lecture, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - E.A. Provine-Chemistry (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - Personal Correspondence-Nell and Mother (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - Special faculty (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Texas
    - Texas University, 1943-1945 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Research Assistant - Biochemistry Institute (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Roger J. Williams (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - E.E. Snell (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - President Homer Rainey (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Campus Activities (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Campus Activities (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Campus Maps (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Citizenship Papers (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Brags (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Faculty Appointment (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Press (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Organic Chemistry Notes (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Master Thesis (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Thess Summary (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Publication from Thesis (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Graduation (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Organic Chemistry 367K Notebook (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Snell Enzyme Chemistry (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Edith Chu (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Lucile Hac (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Joanne Macow Ravel (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Hilda Rosene (Physiology) (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Loren Rogers-First Woman President (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Alumnae Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Clippings (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Iota Sigma Pi (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Grades
    - Transcripts of Grades- Grade school and High School (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Transcripts of Grades- Cornell, Texas, Ouachita (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Nell's commencement (Box 1, Folder 83)
- II. Teaching
  - The Art of Teaching (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate Teaching
    - Food Safety - Lesson (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Meat Cookery - Lesson (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cookies - Lesson (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - FN 214 Tentative Schedule (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Perecentage solution and standard solution problems, 1948-1958 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - FN 214-215 Student List, 1947-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - FN 214 Examples of Homework, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - FN 214 Lecture Notes, 1953-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - FN 214-215 Examples of Student Evaluations, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - FN 214-216 Exams, 1950-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - FN 214-215 student evaluations, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - FN 214 review problems, 1954, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - FN 214 problems, 1955-1963 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - FN 214 Labs, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - FN 215 Lectures, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - FN 214 prelims, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Course lectures, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - FN 214 Lecture Notes, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - FN 214 Homework, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - FN 215 Lab Discussions, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - FN 215 Lab Manuel Answers (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - FN 215 Homework, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - FN 214-215 Review Questions (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - FN 214-215 Teaching Aides (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Foods 310, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - FN 310, 311 and 315, 1949-1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - FN 403 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - FN 420 and FN 446, 1950-1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Quizzes, 1958-1960 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Lipid methods course material, 1960-1969 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - FN 226-236 Chemistry and its Application to Food, which was a course that was dropped, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - NS 616, 1972-1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - DNS 620, Undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Lab Methods, 1958-1960 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Teaching
    - FN 502 Class Materials (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - FN 502 Class Reports, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - NS 616 Materials (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - NS 616 Students, 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - NS 616 Abstract Titles, 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - NS 616 Abstracts, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - NS 627 Abstract Titles (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - NS 627 Materials (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Early Study of Electronic (Microwave), 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Early Teaching of Electronic Cooking, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Training - Use of Laboratory Equipment (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Training - Ward Laboratory Aids (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Summer Sessions
    - Summer Session, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Summer Session, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Summer Session, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Farm and Home Week
    - 1949 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 1950 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 1955 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 1958 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Farm and Home Week (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Food Seminars
    - Food Seminar, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Food Seminar, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Food Seminar, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Food Seminar, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Food Seminar, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Food Seminar, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Food Seminar, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Extension
    - Fans, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Fans, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Inquiries from the Public (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Extension (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - TV Letters (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Appointments
    - Graduate School of Nutrition- Research Associate Dept. of Biochemistry (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Association of Colleges of Upper New York, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Food and Nutrition Cornell, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Professor Emeritus, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Letters of Appointment to Cornell (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Cornell Appointment Material, 1953-1969 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Cornell Appointment Material, 1951-1981 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Cornell Appointment Material, 1951-1981 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Post Docs
    - Dr. Asha Arya (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Dr. Kalpana Kulshrestha (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Dr. Maria Leja (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Dr. Uma Reddy (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Dr. Devulapalli Sharada (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Professor, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Professor Emerita, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Partial List of Advisees, 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Advisees, 1974-1995 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Graduate and Post-Doctoral Applications (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Graduate Student Theses (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Sabbatic
    - Sabbatic I
      - Pre-Sabbatic I, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 110)
      - Scotland and Beltsville, Sabbatic I (Box 3, Folder 111)
      - Scotland, Sabbatic I (Box 3, Folder 112)
      - Scotland Correspondence, Sabbatic I (Box 3, Folder 113)
      - Beltsville, Sabbatic I (Box 3, Folder 114)
      - Nell's letters from Scotland (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Sabbatic II
      - Sabbatic II (Box 3, Folder 116)
      - RT French, Sabbatic II (Box 3, Folder 117)
      - Poland Information, Sabbatic II (Box 3, Folder 118)
      - Poland Correspondence, Sabbatic II (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Sabbatic III
      - EPA, Sabbatic III (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Sabbatic IV
      - Australia, Sabbatic IV (Box 3, Folder 121)
      - New Zealand, Sabbatic IV (Box 3, Folder 122)
- III. Potato Research (Box 13)
  - Regional Research
    - Manual for Cooperative Regional Research (Box 13, Folder 0)
    - Hatch Project 110, 1958-1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Hatch 110 Progress Reports, 1954-1962 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Research Budgets, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Hatch 272, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Northeast Regional Research
      - NEM 30
        - NEM 30 Progress Report - Tech Meeting, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - NEM 30 Technical Committee in Providence, Rhode Island, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - NEM 30 Progress Reports for Rhode Island, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Publications (Box 1, Folder 51)
        - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 52)
        - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 53)
        - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 54)
        - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 55)
        - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 56)
        - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 57)
        - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 58)
        - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 59)
        - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 60)
        - Reports, 1967, 1968, 1970, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 68)
        - 1971 (Box 11, Folder 69)
        - 1966-1975 (Box 11, Folder 70)
      - NE 116
        - Publications and Meeting Places (Box 1, Folder 61)
        - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 62)
        - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 63)
        - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 64)
        - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 65)
        - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 66)
        - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 67)
        - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 68)
        - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 69)
        - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 70)
        - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 71)
        - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 72)
        - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 73)
        - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 74)
        - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 75)
        - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 76)
        - Manual for Regional Research (Box 11, Folder 71)
        - Mondy Elected First Chairwoman, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 72)
        - Mondy Presiding, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 73)
        - Outline, 1977-1982 (Box 11, Folder 74)
        - Other Participants (Box 11, Folder 75)
        - Meeting Places and Date of Meetings, 1977-1992 (Box 11, Folder 76)
        - Minutes and Annual Reports, 1978-1991 (Box 11, Folder 77)
        - Memo, 1979-1992 (Box 11, Folder 78)
        - Progress Report, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 79)
        - Progress Report, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 80)
        - Progress Report, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 81)
        - Progress Report, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 82)
        - Progress Report, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 83)
        - Progress Report, 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 84)
        - Progress Report, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 85)
        - Progress Report, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 86)
        - Progress Report, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 87)
        - Progress Report, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 88)
        - Progress Report, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 89)
        - Progress Report, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 90)
        - Proposal, 1988-1993 (Box 11, Folder 91)
        - Proposal Update, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 92)
        - Meeting - Washington DC, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 93)
        - Mondy Reports, 1987-1991 (Box 11, Folder 94)
        - Hayakawa, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 95)
        - Overall Report (Box 11, Folder 96)
        - Publications of Other Cornell Professors, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 97)
        - Mondy Selected as Emeritus Member - Letters evaluate, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 98)
        - Reprints and Examples of Mondy Publications (Box 11, Folder 99)
        - Publications, 1977-1993 (Box 11, Folder 100)
        - NE116 Progress Report Orono, Maine (Box 14, Folder 54)
      - NE 94
        - NE-94 (Box 1, Folder 77)
        - NE 94 Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Proposals
    - Rules for Submitting Proposals for Competitive Grants (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - General Proposal Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Effect of Sprouting and Sprout Inhibition on the Nutritive Value and Quality of Potatoes, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Northeast Regional Research 116 Revised "Quality Maintenance and Nutritive Aspects of Vegetables During Processing and Storage", 1988-1993 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Cultural Factors Affecting Nitrate Content of Potatoes, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Review by Mondy for National Science Foundation, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Nitrate Proposal, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Factors Affecting Nitrates and Glycoalkaloid Content of Potatoes, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - NSF - Effect of Processing on Nutrient Composition (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Factors Affecting Glycoalkaliod Content of Potatoes (Hatch 422), 1982 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Agricultural Research and Development Grants Program, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - New York State Agriculture and Marketing Board, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Ag and Marketing Grant Proposal, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - NE 94 Glycoalkaloids, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lit Review backing proposal on "Effects of Stress on Potato Quality" (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Effect of Stress on the Composition and Nutritive Quality of Potatoes, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Maleic Hydrazide Proposal, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Maleic Hydrazide: Its Safety and Effect on Potatoes, 1977-07 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Maleic Hydrazide: Its Safety and Effect on Vegetables, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Maleic Hydrazide: Its Safety and Effect on Vegetables, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Blackspot Proposals (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - National Potato
    - National Potato Council Action Letter, 1993-03-1993-04 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - National Potato Research Proposal ($13,697,000), 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - National Potato Council - Celebrate fifty years, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Potato Association of America
    - Elected Honorary Life Member, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Recognition of Life Membership - PAA Journal, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Recognition of Full Professor - PAA Journal, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Potato Friend gets World Food Prize, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - On Editorial Board - Paper Review (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Charter Member - Physiology Committee (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Physiology and Blackspot Committee, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Site Selection Committee - Mondy Chair (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Mondy-Secretary of Utilization Committee, 1980-1989 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Membership of Utilization Section PAA, 1980-1984 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Cornell Potato Work Group (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - New York State Potato Advisory Board (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Annual Meetings Places (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Meetings, 1961, 1968, 1972, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Big Rapids, MI - Mondy on Program, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Charlottetown, Prince Edwards Island, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Monterey, California, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Meeting in Ithaca, 1986-07-27-1986-07-31 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - National Meeting program in Ithaca, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - National Meeting in Oregon, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Colorado Springs, CO, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - General Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - PAA Insider, 2002-04 (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Commercial Potato Production in North America, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - National Potato Council Yearbook, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - USDA Potato FactsYearbook, 1991, 1992, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - NY Potato ReportsYearbook, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - List of Potato Publications (Box 13, Folder 56)
    - Proceedings of 10th Potato Utilization Conference Idaho Falls, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Proceedings of 13th National Potato Utilization Conference Riverhead LI, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Proceedings of 11th National Potato Utilization Conference Gainesville, Florida, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Proceedings of 10th Potato Utilization Conference Presque Isle, Maine, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Scotts Bluff Nebraska, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Proceedings of 19th Potato Utilization Conference Big Rapids, Michigan, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 56th Annual Meeting Twin Falls, Idaho, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 57th Annual Meeting Guelph, Ontario, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 58th Annual Meeting Pasco Washington, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 59th Annual Meeting Beltsville, Maryland, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Site Selection Committee, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - General Overview, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Examples of PAA Insider, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Vancouver Canada Site Committee, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Orlando Florida Site Committee, 1978-04 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - 61st Annual Meeting of PAA Frederiction NB, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Proceedings of 19th National Potato Utilization Conference Big Rapids, Michigan, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - 66th Annual Meeting Monterey, California, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - 68th Annual Conference Presque Isle, Maine, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 32)